College English Test, Band 6,
Part 2, Listening Comprehension Section A, Directions In this section, you will hear
two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear four questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1, with a single line through the
center. Conversation 1
One of the most interesting experiments with dolphins must be one done by Dr.
Jarvis Bastian. What he tried to do was to teach a male dolphin called Buzz and a
female called Doris to communicate with each other across a solid barrier.
how did he do it exactly?
Well, first of all he kept the two dolphins together in the same tank and taught
them to press levers whenever they saw a light.
The levers were fitted to the side of the tank next to each other.
If the light flashed on and off several times, the dolphins were supposed to press
the left -hand lever, followed by the right -hand one.
If the light was kept steady, the dolphins were supposed to press the levers in
reverse order. Whenever they responded correctly, they were rewarded with fish.
Sounds terribly complicated.
Well, that was the first stage.
In the second stage, Dr.
Bastian separated the dolphins into two tanks.
They could still hear one another, but they couldn't actually see each other.
The levers and the light were set up in exactly the same way, except that this time
it was only Doris who could see the light, indicating which lever to press first.
But in order to get their fish, both dolphins had to press the levers in the correct
order. This meant of course that Doris had to tell Buzz whether it was a flashing
light or whether it was a steady light.
did it work?
Well, amazingly enough, the dolphins achieved a 100 success rate.
1 to 4 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 1. What is the purpose of Dr.
Bastian's experiment?
Question 2. What were the dolphins supposed to do when they saw the steady light?
Question 3. Question How did the second stage of the experiment differ from the
first stage? Question 4.
What can we learn from the experiment?
This week's program, Up Your Street, takes you to Harrogate, a small town in
Yorkshire. Harrogate became a fashionable resort during Victorian times when people
came to take a bath in the mineral waters.
Today, few people come to visit the town for its mineral waters.
Instead, Harrogate has become a popular town for people to retire to.
Its clean air, attractive parks, and the absence of any industry make this an ideal
spot for people looking for a quiet life.
Now, to tell us more about Harrogate, I have with me Tom Percival, President of the
Chamber of Commerce.
Tom, one of the things a notices about Harrogate is the large area of open parkland
right down into the middle of the town.
Can you tell us more about it?
Yes, certainly. The area is called the Why the Stray?
It's called that because in the old days people let their cattle stray on the area,
which was common land.
I see. Then, with changes in farming and in land ownership, the Stray became part of
the land owned by Harrogate.
And is it protected?
Oh yes, indeed.
There's a special law.
No one can build anything on the Stray.
It's protected forever.
So it'll always be parkland?
That's right. As you can see, some of the Stray is used for sports fields.
I believe it looks lovely in the spring.
Yes it does.
There are spring flowers under all the trees.
And people visit the town just to see the flowers.
Questions 5 to 8 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 5 Where does this conversation most probably take place?
Question 6 What do we learn about modern Harrogate?
Question 7 What What does the man say about the area called the
Question 8 What attracts people most in the Stray during the springtime?
Section B Directions In this section you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Passage 1 Russell Fazio, an Ohio State psychology professor who has studied
interracial roommates there and at Indiana University, discovered an intriguing
academic effect. In a study analyzing data on thousands of Ohio State freshmen who
lived in dorms, he found that black freshmen who came to college with high
standardized test scores earned better grades if they had a white roommate, even if
the roommate's test scores were low.
The roommate's race had no effect on the grades of white students or low -scoring
black students. Perhaps, the study speculated, having a white roommate helps
academically prepared black students adjust to a predominantly white university.
That same study found that randomly assigned interracial roommates at Ohio State
broke up before the end of the quarter about twice as often as same -race roommates.
Because interracial roommate relationships are often problematic, Dr.
Fazio said, many students would like to move out, but university housing policies
may make it hard to leave.
At Indiana University, where housing was not so tight, more interracial roommates
split up, he said.
Here at Ohio State, where housing was tight, they were told to work it out.
The most interesting thing we found was that if the relationship managed to continue
for just 10 weeks, we could see an improvement in racial attitudes.
Dr. Fazio's Indiana study found that three times as many randomly assigned
interracial roommates were no longer living together at the end of the semester
compared with white roommates.
The interracial roommates spent less time together and had fewer joint activities
than the white pairs.
Questions 9 to 12 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 9. What do we know about Russell Fazio?
Question 10. Who benefited from living with a white roommate according to Fazio's
Question 11. What did the study find about randomly assigned interracial roommates
at Ohio State University?
Question 12. What did Dr.
Fazio find interesting about interracial roommates who had lived together for 10
weeks? Passage 2.
In a small laboratory at the Medical University of South Carolina,
Dr. Vladimir Mironov has been working for a decade to grow meat.
A developmental biologist and tissue engineer, Dr.
Mironov is one of only a few scientists worldwide involved in bioengineering
cultured meat. It's a product he believes could help solve future global food crises
resulting from shrinking amounts of land available for growing meat the old
fashioned way. Growth of cultured meat is also underway in the Netherlands.
Mironov told Reuters in an interview, in the United States it is science in search
of funding and demand.
The new National Institute of Food and Agriculture won't fund it.
The National Institutes of Health won't fund it.
And NASA funded it only briefly, Mironov said.
It's classic disruptive technology, Mironov said.
any new technology on the market on average costs $1 billion.
We don't even have $1 million.
Director of the Advanced Tissue Biofabrication Center in the Department of
Regenerative Medicine and Cell Biology at the Medical University,
Mironov now primarily conducts research on tissue engineering or growing of human
organs. There is an unpleasant factor when people find out meat is grown in a lab.
They don't like to associate technology with food,
said Nicholas Genovese, a visiting scholar in cancer cell biology.
But there are a lot of products that we eat today that are considered natural that
are produced in a similar manner, Genovese said.
Questions 13 to 15 are based on the passage you have just heard.
What does Dr.
Mironov think of bioengineering cultured meat?
Mironov say about the funding for their research?
Question 15. What does Nicholas Genovese say about a lot of products we eat today?
Section C. Directions.
In this section, you will hear three recordings of lectures or talks, followed by
three or four questions.
The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet one, with a single line through
the center. Recording one.
morning, everybody. It is my pleasure to introduce our speaker for today's lecture,
Dr. Howard Walcott.
Dr. Walcott has written numerous articles on the topic of stress management.
Today, he will talk about how to deal with stress and pressure.
Welcome, Dr. Walcott.
Hello, everyone. Today's lecture will focus on how to fight against stress.
Every human being experiences stress in life.
Our tiring jobs, faulty eating habits, and pollution may add to the cause of stress.
Everyone reacts to stress differently.
Some can cope with it, and some cannot.
Studies have proved that an increase in stress hormones might speed up cognitive
decline in people as you age.
When you feel stress, your body produces chemicals which lead to an increase in
blood pressure, high blood sugar levels, and, in the worst case, may lead to major
organ damage. So, it is important to fight against stress before it troubles you.
Here are some of the most effective natural stress reducers.
Music therapy. How about a prescription for ear -soothing music to fight and
overcome stress and diseases?
Sounds great, doesn't it?
Whether you accept it or not, music affects our daily life, as every human responds
to it. A combination of psychology and counseling, music can act as a healing
therapy to cure several conditions, like depression, personality issues, cancer,
etc. Outdoor walking.
is an inexpensive, low -risk, and the easiest accessible form of exercise.
significantly contributes to enhanced mental and physical health.
Meditation. Meditation is certainly the best way to keep stress at bay.
As studies suggest, daily 25 minutes of focused meditation drastically affects
people's ability to recover under stress.
Massage. you are a massage lover, is one more reason for you to indulge in it more
often, as massage improves vascular function and helps in reducing stress.
Essential oils help to soothe your mind and eliminate anxiety.
Sleep well. Most of us do not care about our sleeping schedule, or do not get
adequate sleep. A good amount of sleep of, 7 to 8 hours is a must to relax your mind
and reduce stress levels.
Exercise. Studies have proved that daily physical exercise helps protect your brain
from stress -induced depression.
One should ensure physical activity like walking, jogging, playing games like tennis
or football, on a daily basis for at least 30 minutes, as it is very good for one's
mind. Positive thinking.
Yes, you heard it right.
Positive thinking plays a major role in combating stress.
It may be a little difficult to think positively in a stressful situation, but
believe it or not, giving positive messages to your mind helps ease anxiety and
helps you remain calm and happy.
Laugh out loud and smile.
No, I am not kidding.
Laughter is the best medicine, is an age -old saying, and holds true in this age,
too. Whenever you face a situation when you are extremely stressed, try laughing, or
if not, at least smile, as it releases chemicals which decrease stress level in the
body. I hope the lecture today will be of help and benefit to you.
Thank you. 16 to 18 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 16. What may add to the cause of stress according to the lecture?
Question 17. What can act as a healing therapy to cure personality issues?
Question 18. What can be the reason for a massage lover to be more obsessed with it
according to the lecture?
Recording 2. Hello everyone.
Last time we talked about the history of television.
Today, I'd like to talk about the roles television has been playing in Americans'
political life. Television has transformed politics in the United States by changing
the way in information is spread, by altering political campaigns, and by changing
citizens' patterns of response to politics.
By giving citizens independent access to the candidates, television diminished the
role of the political party in the selection of the major party candidates.
By centering politics on the person of the candidate, television accelerated the
citizens' focus on character rather than issues.
Television has altered the forms of political communication as well.
The messages on which most of us rely are briefer than they once were.
The stump speech, a political speech given by traveling politicians and lasting
hours, which characterized 19th century political discourse, has given way to the 30
-second advertisement and the 10 -second sound bite in broadcast news.
Increasingly, the audience for speeches is not that standing in front of the
politician, but rather the viewing audience who will hear and see a part of the
speech on the news.
In these abbreviated forms, much of what constituted the traditional political
discourse of earlier ages has been lost.
In 15 or 30 seconds, a speaker cannot establish the historical context that shaped
the issue in question, cannot detail the probable causes of the problem, and cannot
examine alternative proposals to argue that one is preferable to others.
Politicians assert, but do not argue.
Because television is an intimate medium, speaking through it requires a changed
political style that is more conversational, personal, and visual than that of the
old style stump speech.
Reliance on television means that increasingly, our political world contains
memorable pictures rather than memorable words.
Schools teach us to analyze words and print.
However, in a world in which politics is increasingly visual, informed citizenship
requires a new set of skills.
Recognizing the power of television's pictures, politicians craft televisual staged
events called pseudo -event designed to attract media coverage.
of the political activity we see on television news has been crafted by politicians,
their speechwriters, and their public relations advisors for televised consumption.
Sound bites in news and answers to questions in debates increasingly sound like
advertisements. Questions 19 to 22 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 19. What does the talk say about political parties before the introduction
of television? Question 20.
Why was traditional political discourse more successful than televised speeches?
Question 21. What does the speaker mean by stating politicians assert but do not
argue? Question 22.
Why do politicians create staged political events?
A survey is a study, generally in the form of an interview or a questionnaire that
provides information concerning how people think and act.
In the United States, the best -known surveys are the Gallup Poll and the Harris
Poll. As anyone who watches much as the news during presidential campaigns knows,
these polls have become an important part of political life in the United States.
North Americans are familiar with the many person -on -the -street interviews on
local television news shows.
While such interviews can be highly entertaining, they are not necessarily an
accurate indication of public opinion.
First, they reflect the opinions of only those people who appear at a certain
location. Thus, such samples can be biased in favor of commuters, middle -class
shoppers, or factory workers, depending on which area the news people select.
Second, television interviews tend to attract outgoing people who are willing to
appear on the air, while they frighten away others who may feel intimidated by a
camera. A survey must be based on a precise representative sampling if it is to
genuinely reflect a broad range of the population.
In preparing to conduct a survey,
sociologists must exercise great care in the wording of questions.
An effective survey question must be simple and clear enough for people to
understand it. It must also be specific enough so that there are no problems in
interpreting the results.
Even questions that are less structured must be carefully phrased in order to elicit
the type of information desired.
Surveys can become indispensable sources of information, but only if the sampling is
done properly and the questions are worded accurately.
There are two main forms of surveys, the interview and the questionnaire.
Each of these forms of survey research has its advantages.
An interviewer can obtain a high response rate because people find it more difficult
to turn down a personal request for an interview than to throw away a written
questionnaire. In addition, an interviewer can go beyond written questions and probe
for a subject's underlying feelings and reasons.
However, questionnaires have the advantage of being cheaper and more consistent.
Question 24. What is crucial for an effective survey?
Question 25. What's the advantage of live interviews over questionnaires?
This is the end of comprehension.